<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Clinton Watkins</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-au</language><copyright>© (2021) Clinton Watkins</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/media/icon_hu80bd23e09555bb319d875cc46bfdcc58_40588_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Firm-Level Productivity Predict Stock Returns? (with Takashi Hiroki and Kentaro Iwatsubo)</title>
      <link>/project/tfp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/tfp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Contrary to the findings of previous U.S. studies, we show that the firm-level total factor productivity (TFP) of Japanese manufacturers positively predicts their future stock returns in the cross-section when controlling for relevant risk factors, including those of Fama and French (2015).  Risks related to intangible expenditure, primarily those for research and development (R&amp;amp;D) and personnel, explain a substantial fraction of the predictive power of firm-level TFP, while bankruptcy, macroeconomic, and capital expenditure risks do not. More productive firms trade at a significant premium to less productive firms. This premium compensates investors for risks associated with innovation and human and organizational capital formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keywords:&lt;/em&gt; Firm-level productivity; Total factor productivity (TFP); Cross-section of returns; Intangibles; Research and development (R&amp;amp;D); Organizational capital&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;JEL classification:&lt;/em&gt; D24; G12; G14; G17&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dividend payout policies (with Jason Bennett)</title>
      <link>/project/dp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/dp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Results to come&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arbitrage and Liquidity Across International Platinum Markets (with Kentaro Iwatsubo)</title>
      <link>/project/arb-liq/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/arb-liq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Liquidity and the ability to conduct arbitrage are interrelated. Arbitrage by investors enforces the law of one price. We examine how liquidity and arbitrage influence each other in the platinum futures markets located in New York and Tokyo. Granger causality between the arbitrage and liquidity variables in each direction provides evidence of their endogeneity. Whether arbitrage opportunity leads to an increase or decrease in liquidity depends on the reason the price difference between the two markets has arisen. A demand shock leads to greater liquidity while asymmetric information is toxic to liquidity. Using a Vector Autregression model and intraday data, we show that the relationship between liquidity and arbitrage changes over time in the context of futures based on the same underlying physical commodity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
