<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Courses | Clinton Watkins</title>
    <link>/courses/</link>
      <atom:link href="/courses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Courses</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-au</language><copyright>© (2022) Clinton Watkins</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/media/icon_hu80bd23e09555bb319d875cc46bfdcc58_40588_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Courses</title>
      <link>/courses/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>📊 Behavioural Finance</title>
      <link>/courses/bf/behavioural-finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/courses/bf/behavioural-finance/</guid>
      <description>













&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../courses/bf/bfp.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers such as Daniel Kahneman (winner of the 2002 Nobel Prize in Economics), Robert Shiller (joint winner of the 2013 Nobel Prize in Economics) and Richard Thaler (winner of the 2017 Nobel Prize in Economics) pioneered the application of concepts from psychology to economic and financial decision-making. In behavioural economics and finance, we use principles from psychology to describe how individuals actually make economic and financial decisions, in contrast to the way rational agent models suggest individuals should make decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;objectives&#34;&gt;Objectives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the course, students should be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;distinguish between the approaches and assumptions of conventional and behavioural finance, and discuss the relationship between the two fields.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;explain the behavioural and  psychological influences on economic and financial decision-making.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;apply behavioural finance research and psychological concepts to problems in finance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;interpret experimental evidence generated by researchers in behavioural economics &amp;amp; finance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;faqs&#34;&gt;FAQs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler &#34;  id=&#34;spoiler-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;What will we do in this course?&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We will do examine how psychological factors influence economic and financial decision-making. We will interpret key research findings and run decision-making experiments during class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler &#34;  id=&#34;spoiler-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Are there prerequisites?&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Financial Theories and Applications&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;syllabus&#34;&gt;Syllabus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../courses/bf/syllabus.pdf&#34;&gt;Download the syllabus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>💹 Financial Theories &amp; Applications</title>
      <link>/courses/ft/financial-theories-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/courses/ft/financial-theories-applications/</guid>
      <description>













&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../courses/ft/sb.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-overview&#34;&gt;Course overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is foundation course in finance that focuses primarily on financial markets and instruments, with some coverage of institutions. The course provides students with an understanding of the roles of financial markets, how financial securities are priced and traded, and the structure and functioning of the global financial system. We cover important security pricing and valuation calculations as well as theory and intuition behind the functioning of the financial system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reasons-you-may-wish-to-take-this-course&#34;&gt;Reasons you may wish to take this course&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gain a fundamental level of financial literacy that will be helpful in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.  future business, government or NPO career, and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.  managing your personal finances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prepare for more advanced study of finance, such as courses in Portfolio Management and Behavioural Finance at AIU, or finance courses during study abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn about the functioning of the global financial system so you can understand news about financial developments and the implications for the global economy and society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-objectives&#34;&gt;Course objectives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students’ objectives for the course are as follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand the roles of various financial markets and institutions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand the theory behind valuing financial securities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be able to calculate valuations for financial securities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand how financial securities are traded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand the characteristics of various financial markets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gain a broad understanding of the global financial system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;faqs&#34;&gt;FAQs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler &#34;  id=&#34;spoiler-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Are there prerequisites?&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Mathematics and statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;syllabus&#34;&gt;Syllabus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../courses/ft/syllabus.pdf&#34;&gt;Download the syllabus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🧮 Portfolio Management</title>
      <link>/courses/pm/portfolio-management-investment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/courses/pm/portfolio-management-investment/</guid>
      <description>













&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../courses/pm/corr.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-you-will-learn&#34;&gt;What you will learn&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course is about the theory and practice of investment management. The course covers investment theory and concepts including security valuation, Modern Portfolio Theory, the risk/return trade-off, diversification, and the Black-Litterman Model. We will use these theories to construct portfolios using securities data in excel and R, and create portfolio analytics using R. We will discuss practical aspects of investment management, as well as the current situation of the investment management business in Japan and overseas. We also cover practical aspects of investment management such as investment philosophy, portfolio design, risk management, performance evaluation, ethics and fiduciary duty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;objectives&#34;&gt;Objectives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of this course, students should have a clear understanding of how financial assets are combined into portfolios, and the issues involved in real world portfolio management. Students should be competent in understanding, analysing and constructing investment portfolios comprised of stocks, bonds and alternative assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;faqs&#34;&gt;FAQs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler &#34;  id=&#34;spoiler-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Are there prerequisites?&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Mathematics, Statistics and Financial Theories and Applications&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;syllabus&#34;&gt;Syllabus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../courses/pm/syllabus.pdf&#34;&gt;Download the syllabus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting-up-r-and-rstudio&#34;&gt;Setting up R and RStudio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../courses/pm/intro-r.html&#34;&gt;How to set up R and RStudio on your computer for the course.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>💰 Finance Data Workshop</title>
      <link>/courses/fd/finance-data-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/courses/fd/finance-data-workshop/</guid>
      <description>













&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../courses/fd/rsd.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-overview&#34;&gt;Course overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an intensive workshop-style course that gives students hands-on experience in analysing and modelling financial data, and interpreting the results of analyses. Students will work with financial data from the Nikkei NEEDS database that is used by analysts in the finance industry. The course focusses on the analysis of Japanese stock market and listed corporation data. Analyses will be conducted using the statistical programing language R, and will include the estimation of financial econometric models. Students will conduct analyses during the workshop sessions on their own computers, and use R Notebooks to produce HTML documents containing their code, results and interpretation. This process develops the understanding of basic concepts related to producing verifiable and reproducible empirical analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reasons-you-may-wish-to-take-this-course&#34;&gt;Reasons you may wish to take this course&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop you ability to conduct empirical analyses and interpret results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gain an understanding of stock market data and selected financial models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gain familiarity with the methodology of empirical research and coding in R.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;faqs&#34;&gt;FAQs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler &#34;  id=&#34;spoiler-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;How should I prepare to take the course?&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Students will need their own computer running Windows, Mac OS, or Linux. Students must download and install R and RStudio on their computer at least one week prior to the course following the instructions on this page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;syllabus&#34;&gt;Syllabus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../courses/fd/syllabus_websitev_20211119.html&#34;&gt;Download the syllabus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting-up-r-and-rstudio&#34;&gt;Setting up R and RStudio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../courses/fd/fdw_r_intro_nb_20211218.nb.html&#34;&gt;How to set up R and RStudio on your computer for the course.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🤝 Crossing Borders Without Crossing Borders</title>
      <link>/courses/cb/crossing-borders/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/courses/cb/crossing-borders/</guid>
      <description>













&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../courses/cb/sdg.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-overview&#34;&gt;Course overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aiu.ac.jp/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;AIU&lt;/a&gt; students will work online on a six-week business case project in international teams with students from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hanuniversity.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;HAN University of Applied Sciences&lt;/a&gt;, the Netherlands, with instructors from both universities. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hanuniversity.com/en/research/research-center/international-business/staff-output/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr. Ingrid Van Rompay-Bartels&lt;/a&gt; from HAN and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.clintonwatkins.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr. Clinton Watkins&lt;/a&gt; from AIU will run the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The business case addresses the role and importance of culture in marketing communication related to consumer product promotion and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.un.org/sustainabledevelopment/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sustainable Development Goals&lt;/a&gt;. How do large international firms communicate their commitment to sustainable development goals while promoting their products in different countries? What role does culture play in their adaptation of their messaging and marketing across countries?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For example, how do firms in different countries promote their commitment to reducing plastics pollution?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will work through a series of individual and teamwork guided tasks and reflection. that stimulate intercultural awareness in a business setting and build the business case. An important component of this course is boosting students’ cultural competence and ability to work effectively in international cross-cultural teams in a business setting.&lt;/p&gt;














&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../courses/cb/cb.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reasons-you-may-wish-to-take-this-course&#34;&gt;Reasons you may wish to take this course&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand the importance of cultural competence (intercultural knowledge, skills, awareness and attitudes) in effective cross-border teamwork in a business setting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn about the influence culture has on their actions and on actions of others, and how to adjust behaviour to enhance the quality of work in a culturally diverse team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand the role of culture in marketing communication, theories and concepts on the nature of culture and cultural differences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn about the United Nations Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) as they pertain to business, materiality under different approaches and issues such as greenwashing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;faqs&#34;&gt;FAQs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler &#34;  id=&#34;spoiler-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;What will we do in class?&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Classes will be held jointly for students in Japan and the Netherlands. The sessions will include lectures plus individual and teamwork tasks. Students will be mentored by the instructors during the individual and teamwork tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler &#34;  id=&#34;spoiler-3&#34;&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Who will be in my group for the teamwork?&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Groups will include about five or six students from AIU and HAN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler &#34;  id=&#34;spoiler-4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;How will we meet for the course?&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We will use MS Teams for this course. All teamwork should be done during the class sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;view-the-syllabus&#34;&gt;View the syllabus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../courses/cb/cbwcb_syllabus.html&#34;&gt;View the syllabus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;media-coverage&#34;&gt;Media Coverage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read about Dr. Ingrid Van Rompay-Bartels&#39; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hanuniversity.com/en/news/2022/05/comenius-senior-fellowship-for-project-raising-global-citizens-at-home/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;teaching and research work&lt;/a&gt; related to this course.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>📚 Undergraduate Seminar</title>
      <link>/courses/se/undergrad-research-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/courses/se/undergrad-research-seminar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;this-is-a-research-seminar&#34;&gt;This is a research seminar&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seminar course is designed for you to write a research paper on an appropriate research topic of your choice. Potential research areas include finance, applied econometrics and other areas of empirical analysis in business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;objectives&#34;&gt;Objectives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objectives include developing research, writing, presentation, communication and planning skills. The overall objective is to learn how to conduct, discuss and present research, and produce a high quality research paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparation&#34;&gt;Preparation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will have undertaken appropriate coursework in their area of research interest to prepare for the seminar course. In particular, a good understanding of empirical methods is very important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pitching-research&#34;&gt;Pitching research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will use the “Pitching Research” framework developed by Professor Robert Faff of the University of Queensland to organise and develop your research project. Check Professor Faff’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://pitchmyresearch.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Pitching Research&lt;/a&gt; website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;faqs&#34;&gt;FAQs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler &#34;  id=&#34;spoiler-0&#34;&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;How do I find a research topic?&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Read as many research papers as possible in subjects in which you have taken courses. Discuss research with your professors and adviser. Ask your adviser&amp;rsquo;s opinion on whether your topic ideas are feasilbe, and how they can be improved. Your research question must be clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;syllabus&#34;&gt;Syllabus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../courses/se/syllabus.pdf&#34;&gt;Download the syllabus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../courses/se/study-plan.html&#34;&gt; Seminar outline and model study guide for AIU students.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ψ The Psychology of Economic Decision-making</title>
      <link>/courses/pe/psychology-economic-decision-making/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/courses/pe/psychology-economic-decision-making/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This session will bring economics down to earth and get you thinking about how we think about our world. Three recent winners of the Nobel Prize in Economics, Daniel Kahneman (2002), Robert Shiller (2013) and Richard Thaler (2017), have pioneered the application of behavioural insights from psychology to economic decision-making. Mixing human psychology with a practical understanding of economic incentives and market behaviour, we will explore how understanding human miscalculations can help us make smarter decisions in both our private and professional lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;objectives&#34;&gt;Objectives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explore the biases and heuristics that influence how we perceive the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understand how these biases and heuristics affect economic and financial decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn how to make better decisions for ourselves and our clients or stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>∑ Applied Econometrics (using R)</title>
      <link>/courses/ae/applied-econometrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/courses/ae/applied-econometrics/</guid>
      <description>













&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../courses/ae/Rlogo.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable width=&#34;15%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-overview&#34;&gt;Course overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course exposes students to common econometric techniques that economists use to estimate, test, and forecast relationships between variables in economics and finance. We cover applied econometrics and selective intermediate theory. Students will apply theory to empirical problems using economic and financial data in class and in assignments using the language &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.r-project.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rstudio.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RStudio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-objectives&#34;&gt;Course Objectives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand intermediate econometric theory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand the approaches to econometric methodology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to apply theory appropriately to empirical problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to teach yourself new econometric techniques via replication.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Become competent using R and associated tools for applied econometrics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;syllabus&#34;&gt;Syllabus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../courses/ae/syllabus.pdf&#34;&gt;Download the syllabus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>📈 Economic Development</title>
      <link>/courses/ed/economic-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/courses/ed/economic-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-overview&#34;&gt;Course overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course covers the microfoundations of development, examining theoretical and empirical issues applicable in less-developed country economies. Topics surveyed will include current issues, agriculture and rural development, education, human capital investment, employment and labour markets, population, poverty alleviation, health, credit and financial markets, dealing with risk, technological change and the design and evaluation of development projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;syllabus&#34;&gt;Syllabus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../courses/ed/syllabus.pdf&#34;&gt;Download the syllabus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🏢 Economic &amp; Financial Crises</title>
      <link>/courses/fc/economic-financial-crises/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/courses/fc/economic-financial-crises/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-overview&#34;&gt;Course overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will examine the salient features of past crises in both emerging and developed economies and cover Hyman Minsky’s financial instability model in detail. The course will include aspects of economic history, international macroeconomics, international finance, banking and financial markets, regulation, government finances, international relations and politics. By successfully completing this course, students will develop a deep understanding of economic and financial crises, their causes and consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-objectives&#34;&gt;Course objectives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the course, students should be able to identify and and knowledgeably discuss:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the warning signs ahead of a crisis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the nature of asset price bubbles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the stages of a typical crisis and the different types of crises.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;economic theories of crises, including Minsky’s Financial Instability Hypothesis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;implications of crises for the macroeconomy and financial markets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pros and cons of policy measures used to deal with a crises.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the history and lessons of various financial crises.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;syllabus&#34;&gt;Syllabus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../courses/fc/syllabus.pdf&#34;&gt;Download the syllabus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🇬🇧 Economics Readings in English</title>
      <link>/courses/er/economics-readings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/courses/er/economics-readings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-overview&#34;&gt;Course overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course aims to develop the the ability and confidence of non-native English speaking undergraduates to comprehend and discuss economics in English. The course focuses on discussing economics related topics, not teaching English language. You are required to read, present and discuss various economics topics in English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;syllabus&#34;&gt;Syllabus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../courses/er/syllabus.pdf&#34;&gt;Download the syllabus&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;../courses/er/topics.pdf&#34;&gt;the topic list.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🌐 Financial Markets Workshop</title>
      <link>/courses/fw/financial-markets-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/courses/fw/financial-markets-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-overview&#34;&gt;Course overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course will develop students’ skills in applying economic and financial theory to the real time analysis of macroeconomics, financial markets and investment strategy. The course is conducted in a workshop style. The class sessions be a combination of lectures given by me, student presentations and student led discussion. We will develop a strategy for interpreting and forecasting developments in financial markets and important economies, focussing on cycles and trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-objectives&#34;&gt;Course objectives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the course, students should:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be familiar with the pattern of economic news that shapes the consensus views on future financial asset returns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be able to differentiate signal from noise in the economic news and data flow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;understand the importance and patterns of economic cycles and trends, financial market fluctuations and exogenous shocks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be able to discuss well-reasoned views about what is happening in international financial markets, and be able to present valid counter-views to consensus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;syllabus&#34;&gt;Syllabus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../courses/fw/syllabus.pdf&#34;&gt;Download the syllabus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🌏 International Business</title>
      <link>/courses/ib/international-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/courses/ib/international-business/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-overview&#34;&gt;Course overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an introductory course in international business that examines the economic, management and commercial aspects of international businesses. We will take a global perspective, but also emphasise the perspective of Asian firms and doing business in Asia. Working through Asia-relevant case studies about international businesses is a key part of the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;syllabus&#34;&gt;Syllabus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../courses/ib/syllabus.pdf&#34;&gt;Download the syllabus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🚢 International Trade</title>
      <link>/courses/it/international-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/courses/it/international-trade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-overview&#34;&gt;Course overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course surveys a number of major issues in trade theory and policy, as well as empirical tests of trade models, in the light of recent developments in international economics. Through this course, students should become familiar with the theoretical models of international trade, current issues in trade policy, and application of the theory to less developed country economies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;syllabus&#34;&gt;Syllabus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../courses/it/syllabus.pdf&#34;&gt;Download the syllabus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🏛 Macroeconomics</title>
      <link>/courses/me/macroeconomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/courses/me/macroeconomics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-overview&#34;&gt;Course overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course introduces advanced macroeconomic modelling techniques and their application to the the analysis of business cycle fluctuations. The course has three main parts; we cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the approaches to macroeconomic modelling and analysis;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the empirical properties and modelling of macroeconomic variables, and analyse their interrelationships using vector autoregression and other econometric methods in the software language R;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the standard theoretical macroeconomic models with an emphasis on business cycles, inflation, monetary and fiscal policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-objectives&#34;&gt;Course Objectives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the course, students should be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;familiar with standard frameworks for macroeconomic modelling and analysis;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;able to understand, model (using R) and interpret the empirical behaviour of important macroeconomic variables;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;conversant with the mathematical structure and solution of the macroeconomic models covered in the course and familiar with the simulation of macroeconomic models in R;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;capable of analysing and interpreting the impact of changes in important variables on the macroeconomy, including the impacts of fiscal and monetary policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;syllabus&#34;&gt;Syllabus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../courses/me/syllabus.pdf&#34;&gt;Download the syllabus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
